Guide to the Friedrich Carl Peetz photographs, 1900. RL.01007
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Friedrich Carl Peetz photographs
1900.
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Peetz, Friedrich Carl
RL.01007
1 Linear Feet
The collection comprises a photograph album with 127 black-and-white photographs (several are hand tinted; most are 4.5 x 6 in.) mounted on 22 boards. The album probably belonged to Friedrich Carl Peetz, most likely an officer in the German Navy (Kaiserliche Marine) and crew member of the S.M.S. Hertha during the Boxer Rebellion. The images were mostly taken in Tsingtao (Qingdao), Chefoo (Yantai), Hong Kong, Peking (Beijing), and Shanhaiguan during the Boxer Rebellion in 1900. The photographs document the German involvement in the Rebellion and primarily depict damage to the Taku Forts, German ships (all are identified) and crew, and temples and other historic buildings visited by the Germans in Beijing and other locales in China. Photographs have German captions written in pencil.
Collection Overview
Collection comprises a photograph album with 127 black-and-white photographs (several are hand tinted; most are 4.5 x 6 in.) mounted on 22 boards. The album probably belonged to Friedrich Carl Peetz, most likely an officer in the German Navy (Kaiserliche Marine) and crew member of the S.M.S. Hertha during the Boxer Rebellion. The images were mostly taken in Tsingtao (Qingdao), Chefoo (Yantai), Hong Kong, Peking (Beijing), and Shanhaiguan during the Boxer Rebellion in 1900. The photographs document the German involvement in the Rebellion and primarily depict damage to the Taku Forts, German ships (all are identified) and crew, and temples and other historic buildings visited by the Germans in Beijing and other locales in China. Photographs have German captions written in pencil.
Biographical Note
Friedrich Carl Peetz was most likely a German Naval officer and crew member of the S.M.S. Hertha (part of the German East Asia Squadron) during the German involvement in the Boxer Rebellion in China in 1900.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
Purchase, 2008
Black-and-white photographs; Germany -- History, Naval; Germany -- Foreign relations -- China; China -- Foreign relations -- Germany; China -- Description and travel -- 18th Century; China -- History -- Boxer Rebellion, 1899-1901; Germans -- China; Peetz, Friedrich Carl; Hertha (Cruiser); Germany. Kriegsmarine -- History
- Photograph Album, 1
  - Part of the Eastern wall that was destroyed during battle, 1900; 4.5 x 6.5 in. (Box 1)
  - Sea fort Shanhaiguan that was occupied by allies, 1900; 4.5 x 6 in. (Box 1)
  - Idols in a Chinese temple in Shanghaiguan, 1900; 4.75 x 6.5 in. (Box 1)
  - Peiho River (Han River), China, 1900; 4.75 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Chinese Sampan (boat), probably near Hong Kong, 1900; 4.25 x 6 in. (Box 1)
  - S.M.S. Hertha, 1900; 4.5 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Hong Kong, Kowloon, 1900; 4.5 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Hong Kong, Kowloon, 1900; 5 x 7 in. (Box 1)
  - German-Russian cavalier with two 15 cm S. K. (Krupp), 1900; 4.5 x 6.5 in. (Box 1)
  - Part of the Western Wall, 1900; 4.5 x 6.5 in. (Box 1)
  - Forbidden City, entrance to the Imperial Apartments, Beijing, China, 1900; 4.75 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Four men stand among trees, most likely in or near Tsingtao (Qingdao), China, 1900; 4.5 x 6.5 in. (Box 1)
  - Ancient Chinese Temple, Tsingtao (Qingdao), China, 1900; 5 x 7 in. (Box 1)
  - Government building in Tsingtao (Qingdao), China, 1900; 4.75 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Port of Hong Kong, 1900; 4.5 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Port of Hong Kong, 1900; 3.5 x 4.5 in. (Box 1)
  - Inside the Summer Palace, Pavilion of Precious Clouds (Bronze Pavillion), 1900; 4.75 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Transport steamer "Hannover", 1900; 4.5 x 6 in. (Box 1)
  - S.M.S. Kaiserin Augusta, 1900; 3.25 x 4.5 in. (Box 1)
  - S.M.S. Hertha and other vessels, 1900; 4.5 x 6 in. (Box 1)
  - Captured Chinese Battleship and Hertha, 1900; 4.5 x 6 in. (Box 1)
  - Lama Temple, Beijing, China, 1900; 4.75 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Beijing: In the Forbidden City, 1900; 4.5 x 6 in. (Box 1)
  - Lama Temple, Beijing, China, 1900; 4.5 x 6.5 in. (Box 1)
  - Garden of the Forbidden City, Beijing, China, 1900; 4.5 x 6 in. (Box 1)
  - Temple of Heaven, Circular Mount Altar, Beijing, China, 1900; 5 x 7 in. (Box 1)
  - Langfang Railway Station near Beijing, 1900; 4.75 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Beijing: Summer Palace, Tower of Buddhist Incense in the back, 1900; 4.75 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Beijing: Summer Palace，Longevity Hill, 1900; 4.75 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Woman in a rickshaw, probably in or around Tsingtao (Qingdao), China, 1900; 3.5 x. 5.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Tsingtao (Qingdao) Market Hall, 1900; 4.5 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Lotus flowers, probably near Tsingtao (Qingdao), China, 1900; 3.5 x. 5.25 in. (Box 1)
  - German-Russian Cavalier with parts of the Eastern wall, 1900; 4.75 x 6.5 in. (Box 1)
  - Temple of Literature, Beijing, China, 1900; 4.75 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Storage of the German Infantry in the destroyed German part in Tangku, 1900; 4.5 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - A 15cm Krupp canon that has been demounted during the explosion on the Eastern wall, 1900; 4.5 x 6.5 in. (Box 1)
  - Sihk Soldier of the 6th Regiment of Bengal Native Infantry, Shanghaiguan, 1900; 4.25 x 3.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Chinese lady in Winter clothes, 1900; 4.5 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - In front of the Temple of Heaven, Beijing, China, 1900; 4.75 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Imperial Palace, Beijing, China, 1900; 4.75 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Mandarin of Shanghai-kuan in sedan chair, 1900; 4.25 x 6 in. (Box 1)
  - Group with Zouave and Sihks, 1900; 4.5 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - German magazine in Tangku on the left side of the bank of the Peiho, 1900; 4.5 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Tower of the Chinese Great Wall, near Shanghaiguan, 1900; 4.75 x 6.5 in. (Box 1)
  - Inner City Gate and Tower of the Chinese Great Wall, near Shanhaiguan, 1900; 4.5 x 6 in. (Box 1)
  - Watchtower on the Chinese (Great) Wall, 1900; 4.5 x 6.75 in. (Box 1)
  - Russian naval vessels, 1900; 5 x 6.5 in. (Box 1)
  - Russian naval vessels, 1900; 4.5 x 6 in. (Box 1)
  - South Wall: Seen from West wall, 1900; 4.5 x 6.5 in. (Box 1)
  - S.M.S. Iltis after battle at Taku forts. Damaged chimney, 1900; 4.5 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - British vessel H.M.S. Barfleur off the coast of Taku Forts, China, 1900; 4.5 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Temple of Heaven, Hall of Prayer for Good Harvests, Beijing, China, 1900; 4.75 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Temple, located at the head of Post Street, 1900; 4.75 x 6.5 in. (Box 1)
  - Chinese Teahouse in Cheefoo, 1900; 4.25 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Chinese Theater in Cheefoo, 1900; 4.25 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Port of Hong Kong, 1900; 4.5 x 6 in. (Box 1)
  - Damage to the S.M.S. Iltis from the Battle of Taku Forts, 1900; 4.5 x 6 in. (Box 1)
  - The Taku-forts in the estuary of the Peiho-river, 1900; 4.5 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - View from the S.M.S. Iltis, 1900; 4.5 x 6 in. (Box 1)
  - S.M.S. Hertha, 1900; 4.5 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - S.M.S. Hertha, 1900; 1.5 x 2.25 in. (Box 1)
  - SS Tsingtao, 1900; 3.25 x 4.5 in. (Box 1)
  - S.M.S. Iltis, 1900; 1.5 x 2.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Unidentified building, 1900; 5 x 6.75 in. (Box 1)
  - German Cavalier, seen from the Southern wall, 1900; 4.75 x 6.5 in. (Box 1)
  - Chinese Junks on Beihe River, in front of the village Tongkin, 1900; 4.25 x 6 in. (Box 1)
  - The Meridian Gate of the Forbidden City, Beijing, China, 1900; 4.75 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Summer Palace, Imperial Apartments, Beijing, China, 1900; 4.75 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Boat harbor, Tsingtao (Qingdao), China, 1900; 3.5 x 5 in. (Box 1)
  - Beijing: In the Forbidden City, 1900; 3.75 x 5 in. (Box 1)
  - Scene near Tsingtao (Qingdao), China, 1900; 3.5 x 4.75 in. (Box 1)
  - Taku-forts after being bombed, 1900; 3.5 x 4.5 in. (Box 1)
  - Damaged chimney, 1900; 4.5 x 5.75 in. (Box 1)
  - University, Tianjin, China, 1900; 4.5 x 6 in. (Box 1)
  - Vessels of the German East Asia squadron off the coast of Taku Forts, China, August 1900, 3.25 x 4.5 in. (Box 1)
  - Our fellow Countrymen in China, 1900; 5 x 6.75 in. (Box 1)
  - Stairway to Temple of Literature, Beijing, China, 1900; 4.75 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Fort at Shanhaiguan, China, 1900; 4.75 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Chinese Sampan (boat), probably near Hong Kong, 1900; 5 x 7 in. (Box 1)
  - Hong Kong, Queen Road, 1900; 4.75 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - 15 cm Krupp canon on the Northern wing of the Russian-German Southern fort on the right side of the esturay of the Baihe -River, 1900; 4.75 x 6.5 in. (Box 1)
  - Cannon wall of the sea fort respectively beach batteries, viewed from North to South, 1900; 4.5 x 6.5 in. (Box 1)
  - S.M.S. Fürst Bismarck off the coast of the Taku Forts, China, 1900; 2.75 x 6 in. (Box 1)
  - S.M.S. Kurfürst Friedrich Wilhelm, 1900; 4.5 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Sampans (boats) near Tsingtao (Qingdao), China, 1900; 4.5 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Qingdao in 1900, 4.25 x 17.5 in. (Box 1)
  - Sampan (boat) near Tsingtao (Qingdao), China, 1900; 4.5 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Envelope bearing return address for Friedrich Carl Peetz, 5 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - In the wardroom of S.M.S. Hertha, off the coast of Taku, 1900; 3.25 x 4.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Picture of the destroyed German part of Tangku (Tianjin), 1900; 4.5 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Undamaged main gun powder storage, viewed from Western angle, 1900; 4.5 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - 15cm S.K. (Krupp) on Russian Cavalier, 1900; 4.75 x 6.5 in. (Box 1)
  - Tower of the city wall of Shanghaiguan, seen from the harbor, 1900; 4.5 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Island palace, Imperial City, Beijing, China, 1900; 4.5 x 5.75 in. (Box 1)
  - Marble Boat, Summer Palace, Beijing, China, 1900; 4.75 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Taku Gate, Tianjin, China, 1900; 4.75 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - German Navy personnel of the German East Asia Squadron, 127 ambrotypes (Box 1)
  - View into Shanhaiguan, a sea fort occupied by the allies, 1900; 4.5 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Chinese and Western men pose for a photo by a river, most likely in or near Tsingtao (Qingdao), China, 1900; 4.75 x 6.25 in.. (Box 1)
  - Idols in a Chinese temple in Shanghaiguan, 1900; 4.75 x 6.5 in. (Box 1)
  - German Navy personnel of the German East Asia Squadron, 1900; 8 x 11.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Three men pose for a photo at a pond, most likely in or near Tsingtao (Qingdao), China, 1900; 4.5 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Man operating a guillotine at Tsingtao (Qingdao), China, 1900; 4.5 x 6.5 in. (Box 1)
  - Landscape featuring buildings in mountains, probably near Tsingtao (Qingdao), China, 1900; 3.5 x. 5.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Beijing, China, 1900; 4.75 x 6 in. (Box 1)
  - Southern Wall seen from South, looking over moat. In the back right German cavalier, 1900; 4.5 x 6.5 in. (Box 1)
  - Vessels of the German East Asia squadron off the coast of Taku Forts, China, August, 1900, 4.5 x 6 in. (Box 1)
  - Vessels of the German East Asia squadron off the coast of Taku Forts, China, August 1900, 4.5 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Breakwater near Colombo, Sri Lanka, 1900; 4.5 x 6 in. (Box 1)
  - Mount Lavinia Hotel, Colombo, Sri Lanka, 1900; 8.5 x 10.75 in. (Box 1)
  - Sampan (boat) near Tsingtao (Qingdao), China, 1900; 4.5 x 6 in. (Box 1)
  - Sampan (boat) near Tsingtao (Qingdao), China, 1900; 4.5 x 6 in. (Box 1)
  - S.M.S. Hansa, 1900; 4.5 x 6 in. (Box 1)
  - On board the S.M.S. Hertha, Hong Kong, 1900; 4.5 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - S.M.S. Hertha in the Kowloon Docks, Hong Kong, August 1900, 6 x 4.5 in. (Box 1)
  - On board the S.M.S. Hertha, Hong Kong, 1900; 4.5 x 6 in. (Box 1)
  - City gate in Shanghaiguan, 1900; 4.5 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Chinese in winter clothes, 1900; 4.5 x 6 in. (Box 1)
  - Hong Kong, Victoria Park, 1900; 4.75 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - German police officier in Tsingtao(Qingdao), 1900; 6.5 x 4.75 in. (Box 1)
  - Port of Hong Kong, 1900; 4.25 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - A 15cm muzzleloader that fell from the wall into the fort during battle, 1900; 4.5 x 6.5 in. (Box 1)
  - The same gun emplacement as on preceding image, seen from yard, 1900; 4.5 x 6.5 in. (Box 1)
  - S.M.S. Fürst Bismarck off the coast of Tsingtao (Qingdao), China, 1900; 4.5 x 5.75 in. (Box 1)
  - Three men at the edge of a pond, most likely in or near Tsingtao (Qingdao), China, 1900; 4.5 x 6.5 in. (Box 1)
  - A rickshaw on a bridge, probably in or around Tsingtao (Qingdao), China, 1900; 3.5 x. 5.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Unidentified ship from the German East Asia Squadron, 1900; 4.5 x 6 in. (Box 1)
  - Forbidden City, Beijing, China, 1900; 4.75 x 6.25 in. (Box 1)
  - Three Italian battle ships, 1900; 3.5 x 4.5 in. (Box 1)